-- Usagi Drop Episode 05 --
Hey, Rin.
Wake up.
Come here.
You were just dreaming.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Huh?
Presented by:
Taka Fansubs
I'll have one too.
I used to make them for Grandpa too!
You did?
I want a kitchen knife.
I think you're a little young for that.
They have ones for kids!
Really?
I'll think about it.
Come on, let's eat quickly.
We have to leave soon.
Okay.
Isn't that baby cute?
Sure.
I'm Kawachi, a relative of Kaga Rin-san.
Rin-san, I mean Rin and I are
living together at the moment.
Oh.
Umm, you are Yoshii Masako-san, right?
Rin's mother?
Umm...
Me? Oh, yes.
I want to meet you in person to discuss some things.
I don't mind coming close to where you live, so could you pick a place?
A place? Umm...
Let's see...
How about near the shopping district-
Sorry, but I have no idea where you live.
Kaga Rin
It's so cute!
You made more, Mom?
Did you make this flower too?
I sure did! It's called embroidery.
Wow! You're amazing.
Once you're a little older, I'll show you how to do it.
Really?
You're good with your hands, after all.
So, what are you going to do?
I guess I'll decide after I meet her.
Watch over Rin for a bit.
Daikichi.
This is an important step, so take your time to talk things over.
Your mother wanted to spend some time with Rin anyway.
She wasn't kidding. This really is close to Grandpa's house.
Welcome.
Table for one?
No, there's someone else coming.
Non-smoking, please.
Careful! You might spill it.
My stress just keeps piling up!
I know what you mean.
I'll have an Americano.
Okay, one Americano.
Will that be all?
Yes.
This is great, Saionji-sensei.
I knew I could count on you!
Now, just add a couple of
traumatic events for each character.
Isn't that a bit much?
No, I think it'll be just perfect.
That's strange.
She took every measure to remove all traces of herself from Grandpa's house, yet she still lives so close by?
Well then, I'll leave it up to you, Sensei.
Thank you.
She didn't do a very good job of running away.
Mama, I have to pee!
Okay, just hold on.
Yoshii Masako
Hello, where are you?
Oh, I'm already inside.
Souichi-san?!
No, I'm his grandson.
She looks like a kid.
I'm sorry, you just look so much like him.
It's okay, I've been hearing that a lot lately.
Still, I think Souichi-san seemed more kind.
Yeah.
I brought a picture of Rin.
Oh, thanks.
That was at the beginning of this year.
They were making rice cakes at her daycare.
Wow, she's like a young lady!
Who was calling you "Sensei" earlier?
You saw that?!
But that name...
It's my pen name.
Sorry, I'm a total mess after staying up all night working to meet my deadline.
Did you leave Rin because of your work?
What? Oh...
You made Rin believe you were Grandpa's maid,
but has it been like that since she was born?
Umm, my work was the reason.
But I was also Souichi-san's maid.
I chose not to consider Rin as my daughter even when I was pregnant with her.
Sorry, I don't get what you mean.
I was never well known.
And just when I finally got a big break, I found out I was pregnant.
It's not the kind of job where you can raise a child at the same time.
But Souichi-san said I should have the child.
Every day I'd either work or lay in bed, constantly getting fatter.
But to my surprise, after Rin was born, she was so cute that I began to love her.
She was surprised?
That's why, even though I kept telling
myself I wasn't going to be her mother,
I gave it my all to work and raise her at the same time.
But getting my lifestyle accustomed to daytime was tough,
and because many of my meetings were scheduled at night, I had to stay awake.
It was physically exhausting for me.
I heard that Rin used to stay with you in your apartment at night.
That's right.
Did you go out sometimes at night then?
Well, it was more like the middle of the night.
I'd go out for a bit after she fell asleep.
And sometimes Souichi-san would watch over her.
Rin wakes up in the middle of the night even now, you know.
Didn't you ever consider how she felt when no one was beside her when she woke up?
How else was I supposed to raise her by myself?
Didn't my grandfather want the
three of you to live as a family?
Would it be alright with you if Rin continued to live with me?
Yes.
I'm not her mother anymore.
I can't decide for her.
Even though there's no doubt you gave birth to her?
That's totally unrelated!
What do you actually think of Rin?
Is she dear to you or not?
I'm not sure...
Umm, I have one favor to ask of you.
What is it?
When it's time for her to enter school, please let her use your surname.
Huh? My surname?
If she has a different surname than her guardian's, she might get picked on.
Could you promise me this one thing?
Well, I understand what you're saying,
but I don't think I can make you a promise.
She's always been Kaga Rin. Changing her name like that won't be so easy.
As a woman, I don't really have
any attachment to my surname.
It could change someday anyway.
Rin's a woman too. I'm sure she feels the same way.
Except she's only six.
Anyway, that's not what I meant.
And besides, that's just your personal opinion.
Only one thing matters!
The name Souichi-san gave her, "Rin."
That's all.
Goodbye.
Wait.
I'm a man, so I don't really
understand what you're getting at,
but I'll talk with Rin about it.
Talk with her?
Don't you think it's cruel to ask a girl as young as her to make such a decision?!
I...
I'm only thinking of what's best for Rin.
Besides, it's cruel for us to decide for her.
I'll find out how she feels about it first.
And after the two of us make a decision, I'll let you know of the outcome.
She sounds like a bad egg to me.
How could anyone abandon such a cute girl?
It's absurd!
Well, she still worries about Rin.
She's just a little strange.
She doesn't realize she's dragging others into her problems.
What are you talking about?!
All mothers worry about their children!
But if she really cared about her, she'd come and see her!
Easy, easy, I'm sure she has her reasons.
Here.
What did Grandpa see in her?
That doesn't really matter now.
She did ask that Rin uses my surname once she enters school though.
Well, I agree with that.
It's natural that a child should have
the same surname as their guardian's.
Okay, I get that,
but how do I explain that to Rin?
She already has a real name.
Well, since she's a girl,
her surname will change anyway once she gets married.
That again?!
What do you mean?
If she's going to get teased just because of her name,
why not let her use our surname?
You really think she'll be able to switch names that easily?
Things can be tough, even in elementary school.
I'm positive.
Then I'll adopt her.
What?!
If she's okay with it, I mean.
Then she'll officially be Kawachi Rin.
It's much more natural.
Don't bring up something like that so carelessly!
I'm not being careless!
We have to decide one way or another, right?!
It doesn't matter when we decide!
Now, now...
It does matter!
No, it doesn't!
I'm not going to let Rin be passed around again.
There's no way I could do that to her!
I'll face whatever comes for Rin's sake.
Here you go.
For me?
Yup, for you.
But, you can only use it when I'm with you.
Promise me that and the knife is yours.
Okay!
I know! I'll make curry for you.
Really?
Tonight!
How about tomorrow?
Umm, do I push or pull?
Huh?
Let me try.
Like this.
You're good at that, Daikichi!
Well, I lived by myself for a long time.
Your turn.
Nice and slowly.
Don't drink the water in here.
Okay.
Alright, go down to your shoulders and count to ten.
One, two, three, four, shut the door.
One, two...
Three, four...
Five, six, pick up sticks.
Seven, eight...
Five, six...
Daikichi, faster!
Don't be in such a hurry.
Okay.
Hey, Rin.
What?
Never mind.
It's delicious!
Do I have to gargle that much?
Umm, no.
Hey, Rin...
I'm not your dad.
Yeah.
And I'm not your older brother either, right?
Nobody thinks that!
It's just an example!
So then who am I?
You're Daikichi.
That's just my name.
Listen.
This is only if you're up for it,
but, how should I put it...
Would you...
Would you be okay with me becoming your real dad?
Daikichi? My dad?
Also, your name would change to "Kawachi Rin."
Kawachi Rin...
No.
Are you sure?
Wouldn't it be better if I was your dad?
My dad is Grandpa.
And I like this name, "Kaga Rin."
I like it because it's the same name as Grandpa's.
I see.
You're fine just as Daikichi.
Daikichi, what's wrong?
Are you crying?
It's sweat!
In March?
Be quiet and open your mouth!
It was open, but you were too busy crying!
I said I wasn't crying!
Chin up.
Okay.
This'll always be your home, you know.
I know.
"We can never forget what we believe in,"
Congratulations
on
Graduating
Daycare!
"because the sun will surely rise tomorrow."
"We can never lose what we dream of,"
"because one day they will surely come true."
"Our first step will be towards tomorrow."
"From now on, everything will be new to us."
"We'll become brave and take that first step."
I see.
You'll get fat, you know.
Whatever. I'm useless anyway.
Can I have one?
No.
Only babies are held like that!
That's what Sayaka-chan said.
What are you talking about?
Even adults want to be held like that sometimes!
What? Why?
I'm not really sure.
It's alright? Even if I'm in first grade?
Of course.
I'll hold you no matter how old you get.
What is it?!
I'm sorry!
I should have held you back then!
Huh?
I'll hold you the next time you cry!
What the heck?
Don't worry!
Am I raising Rin? Or is it the other way around?
It's hard to tell sometimes.